以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
所以大家好，我是AlanEdelman和
so hi everybody I'm Alan Edelman and
帮助了一点教这门课
helped a little bit to teach this class
去年但很高兴看到它
last year but happy to see that it's
今年这么好教授
going great this year so professor
斯特朗来教你1806年的一些人
Strang came to teach 1806 some of you
可能知道介绍线性
may know the the introductory linear
代数课程和Strang教授来了
algebra course and professor Strang came
通过并给出了这个伟大的示范
by and gave this great demonstration
关于行等于列
about the row rank equals the column
排名，我想知道，如果你这样做
rank and I'm wondering if you did that
在这个课程中，他们随时都可以
in this class at any time or would they
已经看到它在笔记中很好
have seen that it's in the notes well in
无论如何，就像斯特朗教授一样
in any event just as professor Strang
走了这里，我会抓住这个
walked out so here I'll just grab this
这真的是我真的要开始了
this is truly I was actually gonna start
编写代码来做四边形
writing the code to do the quadrilateral
但是我没有足够的时间
but I didn't have enough time you could
看到我开始，但这是重点
see me starting but here's the point
五个这很容易，所以三角
five for the triangle which was easy so
这与朱莉娅的故事有什么关系
that what's the story with Julia in this
上课了他们用了一点还是一点
class have they used it a little or a
很多或在实验室中你使用过Julia但是
lot or in the labs you've used Julia but
那只是MATLAB，所以那是
that was just MATLAB so that was but
好吧，所以斯特朗教授表示
okay so so so professor Strang showed
这个证明他会放下一个
this proof where he would he put down a
三乘三矩阵它排名第二
three by three matrix it had rank two
并且他展示了你知道的
and he showed the you know took the
你知道前两个的列
columns that were you know the first two
列是独立的，而且是
columns were independent and and was
你很容易知道它很容易显示出来
easy you know it was easy to show the
行排名等于后面的列排名
row rank equals the column rank after
我问道，StrangRoy教授出去了
professor Strang Roy went out I asked
那会对零矩阵起作用吗？
would that work for the zero matrix so
所以这里的零矩阵和自
so here's the the zero matrix and since
我真的不告诉你的证明
I'm not really telling you the proof
我只想说如果我要交配
I'll just say if I were to put a mate if
我是按字面意思制作矩阵的
I were to make a matrix of the literally
这个矩阵的独立列是什么
independent columns of this matrix what
我会这样做吗？
would I do
所以这可能看起来很棘手
so it's zero sort of a might seem tricky
这不是那么棘手，但事实并非如此
it's not really that tricky but this is
你走出去的那一刻我做了什么
what I did the moment you walked out so
所以是的，所以我有三个这三个
so yeah so I've got this three by three
矩阵，我需要迈出第一步
matrix and I need to make a first step
在我需要的证据中
in and whatever the proof was I needed
取字面上的列
to take the columns of the the literally
该矩阵的独立列和
independent columns of this matrix and
把它们放在自己的矩阵中
place them in a matrix of their own what
我会这样做是一个空矩阵
would I do it would be an empty matrix
什么是这个空的大小
what would be the size of this empty
矩阵不完全为零，因为
matrix not exactly zero by zero because
每一列都在我们的每一列
where every every column is still in our
三，你看到了我希望的正确答案
three you see so the right answer I hope
这是有道理的是三乘三
this makes sense is a three by zero
空矩阵，这是一个概念
empty matrix and that's a concept that
存在于MATLAB和Julia及其中
exists in MATLAB and in Julia and in
Python我觉得我很有信心
Python I think I'm sure and in any
计算机语言，所以如果你有一个完整的
computer language so if you had a full
秩3x3矩阵线性独立
rank 3x3 matrix the linearly independent
如果你，列将是三乘三
columns would be three by three if you
排名第二的是三乘二
had a rank two would be three by two
他们已经有一个等级一个矩阵它会是
they've had a rank one matrix it'd be
如果我没有列，那就三个一个
three by one so if I had no columns
零三有意义并完成
three by zero makes sense and to finish
再次证明我不是在说这些
the proof again I'm not telling these
学生们显然是在笔记中
students it's in the notes apparently
下一个矩阵是R和零
the next matrix would be R and of zero
三，当然你和你相乘
three and of course you multiply and you
获得零的三乘三矩阵，
get a three by three matrix of zeros so
很有趣地看到，该证明还
it's fun to see that that proof still
即使没有零矩阵也能工作
works even for the zero matrix without
任何真正的年龄，所以这就是今天嗯
any real age so that was just today um
让我另一件事是让我可以
let me the other thing is let me can I
说一两句关于最近的事情
say a word or two about recent stuff
关于朱莉娅所以我开始整理一个
about Julia so I start to put together a
说它还没准备好，但我会
talk it's not really ready yet but I'll
无论如何要与你分享，所以谷歌做了
share it with you anyway so Google did
朱莉娅世界上周对我很感兴趣
the Julia world a big favor last week I
这意味着这是巨大的，所以你们都知道
mean this is huge so you all know
机器学习很可能很热
machine learning is hot that's probably
为什么你可能在这堂课
why you're here in this class I probably
不必告诉你，但我
don't have to tell you and yet I
如果你们中的一些人不会感到惊讶
wouldn't be surprised if a number of you
对整个这一切都有点希望
were sort of wish the whole this whole
class是Python或者其他东西
class was in Python or something or
也许MATLAB左右我不怀疑
maybe MATLAB or so I don't doubt that
你们中的一些人可能想要那样做
some of you might have wanted that to
发生了，我们受到轰炸
happen and we get sort of bombarded with
你知道为什么Python不是那么多
with you know why not Python not so much
MATLAB了，但你知道为什么不
MATLAB anymore but you know why not
Python是那种而来的问题
Python is sort of the issue that comes
很多，我可以说话直到奶牛
up a lot and I could talk til the cows
回家但没有人会相信我
come home but nobody would believe me
但谷歌上周出来并表示
but Google came out last week and said
说到机器
that that when it comes to machine
学习那里真的有两种语言
learning there really are two languages
它足够强大，可以做机器
that are powerful enough to do machine
学习做机器学习的各种
learning to do machine learning kinds of
你想做的事情和一些事情
things that you want to do and in some
感受今天其余的讲座
sense the the rest of today's lecture
我将给予的意志将是
that I'm going to give will will be
也许这是插图，但如果你
maybe illustrations of this but if you
希望你能去看看他们的
want you can go and look at their their
博客在这里
blog here
他们做的是他们基本上是这样的
what they do is they basically sort of
用一大堆开始比赛
start the the race with a whole bunch of
编程语言有Python
programming languages there's Python
他们是我们的JavaJavaScript
there's our Java JavaScript they they're
你知道他们有点看
you know they they they sort of look at
所有这些语言，如果你读
all of these languages and if you read
你会看到的博客，但我们会
the blog you'll see but we're gonna
根据技术优点和过滤它们
filter them out on technical merits and
然后很多人就会消失
and right away a lot of them disappear
包括Python和Java
including Python and Java
如果你去，他们实际上会花钱
and and they actually spend if you go to
博客，你会看到他们花了很多钱
the blog you'll see they spend a great
因为有关Python故事的时间问题
deal of time on the Python story because
他们知道人们会想要
they know that people are gonna want to
听到一个正确我的意思是，如果人们
hear that one right I mean if people
想要被说服，所以有
want to be convinced and so there's
实际上多个屏幕已满
actually multiple screens full on the
Python之所以不好
the reason why Python is just not good
足够机器学习所以他们
enough for machine learning so they they
留下语言留下juliaswiftc++
leave for languages left julia swift c++
和防锈，然后进行排序，他们的下一个
and rust and then sort of they the next
如果你去的那部分
sort of part of the if you go to the
他们过滤的博客的下一部分
next part of of the blog they filter on
可用性然后再两个咬一口
usability and then two more so to bite
灰尘
the dust
所以c++和锈就消失了
so c++ and rust disappeared and then
他们去说，这些都是
they go on to say that these are the
只有他们认为的两种语言
only two languages they feel are
适合机器学习和
appropriate for machine learning and
他们把这个很好的报价你知道了
they put this nice quote you know that
你知道它有很多共同之处
that you know it shares many common
价值观，他们实际上继续下去
values and they actually go on and about
什么机器学习真正需要和
what machine learning really needs and
你知道吗，我建议你看看
you know yeah i'd recommend you look at
它然后最终当然是他们
it and then finally of course they're
要迅速推动他们的那些
gonna push swift which they which they
应该这样他们有更多的blahblah
should so they had some more blahblah
有关更多的人正在使用可能迅速
about more people are using swift maybe
这是真的我不知道，但是你
it's true i don't know but so that you
知道他们真的会说的是
know they're gonna they really said is
他们对swift和。更熟悉
they're more familiar with swift and
如果我是的话，你知道的朱莉娅
julia which you know if i if I were
说我会说我比我更熟悉
speaking I'd say I'm more familiar than
朱莉娅比斯威夫特所以也许这是公平的
Julia than Swift so maybe it's fair and
然后我开始放一点卡通片
then I started to put a little cartoon
关于编程心理学
on the psychology of programming
语言只是因为它的类型
languages just because it's it's sort of
我和所有人碰到的东西
a something that I bump into with all
人们总是说所有语言的时间
the time people always say all languages
同样好，它不是真的
are equally good it doesn't really
但事实是，如果你不这样做
matter but the truth is if you don't
如果提到一个，请提一种语言
mention a language if you mention a
你尚未使用的语言
language that you're not using yet
你至少要把它调出来
you're gonna tune it out at least until
谷歌出现就是这样
Google comes along so that that's where
我们还好，我就这么说
we are okay enough about I just put this
我知道在你身边测试它
together I know testing it out on you
现在好了，现在让我这样做两个
all right now so now let me do so two
更多的数学事物，所以第一
more mathematical things so the first
我想做的事情是和你谈谈
thing I want to do is talk to you about
前进模式自动
forward mode automatic
分化所以，如果你做了任何
differentiation so if you've done any
自动折旧当然可以
automatic depreciation of course okay so
我觉得这很有趣，我希望你能
I think this is pretty fun I hope you'll
喜欢它
like it
我有一个笔记本，朱莉娅向前跑
I have a notebook and Julia run forward
模式自动分化和
mode automatic differentiation and the
这个笔记本因为我而走到一起
this notebook came together because I
我试图了解什么是大事
was trying to understand what the big
交易是很长一段时间，我有一个
deal was for a long time and and I had a
小麻烦我的意思是它就是这个
little trouble I mean it's it's the
通常的故事，我们是逐行的
usual story we're on a line-by-line
水平它很容易理解，但喜欢
level it's easy to understand but like
这是什么大不了的一部分
what's the big deal part that's that
有时候更难掌握和
sometimes the harder thing to grasp and
和我要去的第一本笔记本
and and the first notebook I'm gonna
告诉你是我的结果
show you is sort of the result of my
试图抓住那样的东西
trying to grasp like what was the the
这里的真实照片和我的第二件事
real picture here and the second thing I
我想我会在黑板上做
think I'll just do on the blackboard
它还没有真正准备好，但我会
it's not even really ready yet but I'll
无论如何，它会释放给你们
sort of unleash it on you folks anyway
是告诉你如何做一个特定的
is to show you how to do a particular
自动向后模式的示例
example of backward mode automatically
反向传播的发音
pronounciation the backpropagation let
你在神经网络和II猜测中看到了
you see in a neural net and I I guess
你已经看到了一些自己的东西
you have seen some their own that's here
实际上他们现在可能是每个人的
so actually they might now everybody's
看到神经网我觉得你知道两个
seen neural nets I think you know two
从现在起几年，它将处于高度低点
years from now it'll be in height low
高中和那里三年
high schools and three years from there
将在幼儿园我不知道
will be in kindergartens I don't know
每个人都看到神经网似乎是
everybody see neural nets seem to be
那种他们并不难
sort of they're not that hard to
明白没关系，让我开始吧
understand okay so let me let me start
关闭的事情，真的是两件事
things off and really the two things
我要说服你的是
that I'd left to convince you of is
让我在这里找到我的订单
let's let me just find here's my ordered
如果事情是我真的两件事
if thing the two things that I really
想要说服你，也许你
want to convince you of and maybe you
已经相信其中一些是那个
already believe some of this is one that
好吧，也许你还不相信这一点
well maybe you don't believe this yet
但是语言很重要
but that the language matters in a
正确的数学意义
mathematical sense that the right the
正确的计算机语言可以做到
right the right computer language can do
更多的是为你而不仅仅是采取一些
more for you than just take some
黑板上的算法和实现
algorithm on a blackboard and implement
它可以做到它可以做更多
it you could do it could do much more
这是我希望的
and this is something that that I hope
举几个例子和另一个例子
to give a few examples of and the other
我打赌你们都相信的事情
thing that I bet you all are believed
现在因为你已经上过这堂课了
now because you've been in this class is
那是线性代数的基础
that that linear algebra is the basis
一切每门课程应该开始
for everything every course should start
线性代数我的意思是它
with linear algebra I mean that's it to
我感觉这是一次不幸的事故
me it feels like a unfortunate accident
那个线性代数来的历史
of history that that linear algebra came
由于太多原因等等太晚了
too late for too many reasons and and so
经常会有更好的事情
very often things that would be better
与线性代数做得都
done with linear algebra are
不，而且我的意思是，如果对我来说
not and and and I mean it if to me it
感觉就像没有做物理
feels like doing physics without
微积分就像我只是不明白
calculus like I just don't get it
就像我知道高中那样做但是它
like I know high schools do that but it
只是看起来不对，你知道我喜欢
just seems wrong you know it to me like
你知道所有的工程
you know all of engineering all it
应该都是线性代数我的意思是我
should all be linear algebra I mean I'm
我只相信几乎所有可能都没有
I just believe that almost all maybe not
所有，但比大多数颇多
all but quite a lot more than most
人们意识到我会说好的，所以让
people realize I would say okay so let
我从自动差异开始
me start with automatic differentiation
所以我要从这个故事开始
so so I'm gonna start by this story by
告诉你我会去
telling you that I would go to
会议我会去数字
conferences I would go to numerical
分析会议我会听到人们的意见
analysis conferences I would hear people
谈论自动分化我是
talk about automatic differentiation I'm
说实话，我正在看我的电子邮件
gonna be honest I was reading my email I
进行了调整出像谁在乎像
was tuned out like who cares about like
我知道微积分我可以教
I know calculus I could you could teach
一台电脑，我不知道我是谁
a computer to do it I don't you know I'm
对我来说似乎很容易，我的意思是我确定
seems pretty easy to me I mean I'm sure
有技术细节，但它
there are technical details but it
教一个人似乎并不那么有趣
didn't seem that interesting to teach a
计算机区分我有点
computer to differentiate I sort of
认为它是相同的微积分
figured that it was the same calculus
我在学习微积分时学到了什么
that I learned when I took a calculus
你知道的课，你知道你
class you know here you know you you've
记住这张桌子，你教给它一个
memorized this table you teach it to a
电脑，你知道你学习链
computer you know you learn the chain
规则和产品规则和
rule and the product rule and the
商数规则并且你碰到了你
quotient rule and bump you you did the
电脑正在做我想做的事
computer is doing just what I would do
它用纸和铅笔这么重要我
it with paper and pencil so a big deal I
是不是我没注意到任何一个
was I didn't pay attention and in any
事件有说有点有
event there was said a little there was
这个小神经元在我的背后
this little neuron in the back of my
大脑说嘿，也许我错了
brain that said hey maybe I'm wrong
也许它正在做有限的差异你
maybe it's doing finite differences you
知道你采取的那种事情
know the sort of thing where you take
你把dy-by-dx带入了
the the the you take the d-y-by-dx in
一些数字方式，你做的
some numerical way it's you do the
有限差异和激进
finite differences and in the radical
分析他们应该告诉你
analysis they're supposed to tell you
你知道如果你的H太大了吗？
you know if H is too big you get
如果你有一件T太截断误差
truncation error if you have a t too
小你得到了舍入错误和
small you get roundoff error and the
真相是没有人告诉过你是什么
truth is nobody ever tells you what's a
好年龄，但你去数字
good age but you go to numerical
分析课希望有人会
analysis class hoping somebody would
告诉你，但无论如何，所以我
tell you but but in any event so I
想也许就是这样的
thought maybe it was that kind of a
数值有限差分和和
numerical finite difference and and and
我认为对我来说最大的惊喜是
and I think the big surprise for me was
自动分化是
that automatic differentiation was
既不是第一件事，也不是第二件事
neither the first nor the second thing
实际上还有第三件事
that there's actually a third thing
有些不同
something different
那不是第一个或第二个
that's neither the first or the second
我发现那令人着迷和
that I found that fascinating and and
也许我甚至会告诉你它是如何击中的
maybe I'll even tell you how how it hit
我知道这就是故事
me in the head that this was the story
因为我真的没有注意
because I really wasn't paying attention
但我喜欢这种奇异的价值
but I loved the singular value
分解我很高兴看到这一点
decomposition I'm glad to see that
人们正在绘制抛物线和四分之一
people are drawing parabolas and quarter
圆和搞清楚什么的
circles and figuring out what the the
这个东西是最小的SVD值
minimum SVD value is this thing right is
只是你知道的
is just you know the
只是你知道上帝给人类的礼物
it's justyou know God's gift to mankind
它只是一个很好的分解和一个
it's just a good factorization and one
我会玩的东西
of the things that I would I was playing
与朱莉娅一起计算
with with with Julia was to calculate
SVD的雅可比矩阵也是如此
the the Jacobian matrix for the SVD so
所以你知道所有的矩阵因子分解
so you know all matrix factorizations
只是改变变量就是这样
are just changes of variables right so
如果你有一个正方形的话
if you have an if you have a square
矩阵n由SVD宝贝我确定你
matrix n by n the SVD babe I'm sure you
知道这是你知道的U矩阵
know this is you know the the U matrix
实际上是n倍n减去1比2
is really n times n minus one over two
变量也是V和Sigma所具有的
variables so is the V and the Sigma has
有n个变量把它们放在一起
got n variables put it all together you
N平方所以它只是一个变化
got N squared so it's just a change of
变量和每次改变
variables and every time you change
变量你可以形成那个大矩阵n
variables you can form that big matrix n
你知道N平方的平方
squared by N squared of the you know
dy/dx计算其决定因素并得到
dy/dx compute its determinants and get
答案，我想让你知道
an answer and and I want you to know
我真想知道的是什么
what that I wanted to actually knew the
对于和我想的理论回答
theoretical answer for that and I wanted
看电脑确认一下
to see a computer confirm that
理论答案和我谈到了一些
theoretical answer and I spoke to some
在非非洲写过奥托蒂芬的人
people who who wrote Otto Tiffin in non
giulia语言和我很惊讶
giulia languages and I was surprised by
答案他们说哦，是的，我们可以
the answer they said oh yeah we could
教我们系统的答案我说
teach the answer to our system I said
你是什么意思，你可以教导
what do you mean you could teach the
回答为什么不只是计算
answer why doesn't just compute the
回答你要教的答案
answer what you have to teach the answer
我认为那是错的，因为在
I thought that was all wrong because in
朱莉娅，我们没有必要教它
Julia we didn't have to teach it it
实际上它实际上会计算它
actually it would actually calculate it
哦，然后我开始明白了
oh and then I started to understand a
更多关于auto-da-fé的内容
little bit more about what auto-da-fé
正在做和朱莉娅正在做的事情
was doing and what Julia was doing and
所以这就是这款笔记本的样子
so this is how this notebook came to be
所以，让我开始，我说太多了
so let me start I'm saying too much let
我从一个可能的例子开始
me start with an example that that might
有点打击家，所以我要去计算
kind of hit home so I'm going to compute
x的平方根我真的很简单
the square root of x I'm a real simple
例如你知道平方根很漂亮
example you know square roots pretty
我最老的时候会很容易的
easy I'm gonna take when the oldest
人类已知的算法
algorithms known to mankind
巴比伦人的平方根算法吧
the Babylonians square root algorithm it
说你知道从一个开始开始
says you know start with a starting
猜猜可能它有点太低了
guess T maybe it's a little bit too low
对于x的平方根，得到x超过T所以
for the square root of x get x over T so
这将是太大继续前进，
that would be too large go ahead and
取平均值，并重复没关系，这是
take the average and repeat okay this is
相当于牛顿的方法
equivalent to a Newton's method for
求平方根，你知道这是
taking the square root and you know it's
已经知道了几千年人类如此
been known for millennia to mankind so
你不知道它不是非常糟糕
it's not a terribly you know it's not
无论如何最新的研究
the latest research by any means for
计算平方根，但它的工作原理
computing square roots but it it works
非常有效，这里有点
very effectively and here's a little
Julia代码实际上会很好
Julia code that actually will well will
实现它可能看起来像代码
implement it it probably looks like code
用任何语言，所以我要开始
in any language so I'm gonna start off
一个人
at one so
从字面上看，我只需要一个加号
literally I'm just gonna take one plus
起始值X除以2
the starting value X and divide by two
然后我会重复好的，你
and then I'm gonna repeat okay and you
你知道我们可以，我们可以检查
know you can we we can check that the
算法在这里工作的alphasPI等
algorithm works here's alphas PI and so
我将采用巴比伦算法和
I'll take the Babylonian algorithm and
将它与朱莉的内置和你比较
compare it to Julie's built-in and you
看到它给这里给出了正确的答案
see it gives gives the right answer here
它是你知道的两个平方根
it is with square root of two you know
总是很好检查你的代码
always good to check your your code
工作还好，即使我喜欢看东西
works okay even I like to see things
图形所以我跑了算法
graphically so I ran the algorithm for
很多X值，你甚至可以
lots of values of X and you could even I
喜欢做这个，我有种想，在
love doing this I kind of wished that in
前面讲我这是什么，如果
the previous talk I was this is what if
我只工作速度不够快我
I'd only worked fast enough I was
实际上我去建了一个粘糊糊的
actually I went to build a little gooey
我可以在哪里移动点数
where I could move the points and in
你眼前，也许你有一个在
front of your eyes maybe you have one in
MATLAB我打赌你这样做，但我想
MATLAB I bet you do but I wanted to
建立它，但他们没有快速到达那里
build it but they didn't get there fast
不够好，但在这里，这是一个诸如此类的事情
enough but here this is a sort of thing
我想看到我收敛
and I'd like to see the convergence I
意思是所以你可以看到数字
mean so you could see the digits
将抛物线收敛于
converging the the the parabola on the
底部黑色是的平方根
bottom the black is the square root of
当然所以它就是这样的
course so there it is there's the
我想得到的巴比伦算法
Babylonian algorithm I would like to get
平方根的导数但是
the derivative of square root but the
游戏规则是我不会去的
rules of the game are I'm not going to
类型方法一或方法二我不是
type method one or method two I'm not
去做你永远不会看到我输入1/2
going to do you'll never see me type 1/2
X到负1/2，这对你来说都是正确的
X to the minus 1/2 that's right you all
知道这是我不会的衍生物
know that's the derivative I will not
打字，我不会，它不会来
type that I will not it's not gonna come
Juliaok和第二个
anywhere from Julia ok and the second
事情是我不会做有限的事情
thing is I'm not gonna do a finite
区别我会没事拿到
difference all right I'm gonna get that
平方根，但不是通过某种方式
square root but not by by by sort of
要么是我确定你的两件事
either the two things that I'm sure you
会想到没问题但是这是怎么回事
would think of alright but here's how
我要去做，而且我要去做
I'm gonna do it and and I'm gonna do a
朱莉娅码点点就会有
little bit of Julia code there'll be
八条朱莉娅，但我不会
eight lines of Julia but I'm not gonna
完全说它是如何工作的我会
completely say how it works yet I'll
也许我会让你陷入悬念
I'll keep you in suspense for maybe
大约五分钟，然后我会说
about five minutes and then I'll tell
你是如何工作的
you how it how it works
好吧所以这里有八行朱莉娅
all right so here's eight lines of Julia
代码，这将得到平方根
code that will get me the square root so
在这三行中，我要创造一个
in these three lines I'm gonna create a
朱莉娅类型我要把它称为d4
julia type i'm gonna call it a d4 for a
双数这是去一个名字
dual number which is a name that goes
回到至少一个世纪或许更多
back at least a century maybe more so
我要创建一个d型和所有这些
i'm gonna create a d type and all this
是一对漂浮物好吧所以它是一个
is is a pair of floats okay so um it's a
它会带有一对花车的元组
tuple with a pair of floats it's gonna
可这将是某种
be it's going to be some sort of
数值函数和导数对
numerical function and derivative pair
好吧，我的八条线中有三条是
all right so three of my eight lines is
创造一个d--这意味着享受你的
to create a d-- this means enjoy your
语言
language
这意味着使用数字的子类型
this means to use a subtype of a number
所以我们会把它当成一个数字
so we're gonna treat it like a number
对，我们希望能够增加倍数
right we want to be able to add multiply
并划分这些有序的对，但
and divide these these ordered pairs but
它只是一对数字而不是
it's just a pair of numbers right don't
得到-不要朱莉娅吓唬你，只是
get--don't the Julia scare you it's just
函数导数数字对
a function derivative numerical pair
好吧，这些其他五行是什么
okay and what's these other five lines
好吧，我想教它一些规则
well I want to teach it to some rule in
商数规则让大家记住
the quotient rule so you all remember
总和规则我猜这很容易
the sum rule I guess that's the easy one
该商数规则仍然还是有
the quotient rule is still I still have
你知道我高中的老师
the my teacher from high school you know
你知道，在我耳后响起
ringing in the back of my ear you know
分母时候，它是
the denominator times it was the
分子减去你所有的分子
numerator minus the numerator you all
有顺口溜和你的工作你
have that jingle and you're working your
大脑过于我打赌你被划分
brain too I bet you do divided by the
分母平方
denominator squared
甚至不能把它弄出来我的头，以便最大
can't even get it out of my head so up
所以有商数规则等等
so so there's the quotient rule and so
我们在这五行中做了什么
what are we doing in these five lines
首先，我想超载
well first of all I want to overload
加分和其他一些东西
plus and divide and a few other things
朱莉娅要我说你确定吗
and Julia wants me to say are you sure
所以你说的方式是肯定的
so the way you say are you sure is that
我要进口加分并除以你
I'm going to import plus and divide you
知道，因为这是危险的
know because it'd be dangerous to play
加上所以我在这里加两个
with plus so here I'm gonna the plus two
双数字我们要添加
dual numbers we're gonna add the
功能和衍生物分为两个
function and the derivatives divide two
双重数字，我们将分裂
dual numbers we're gonna divide the
函数值和分母时间
function values and denominator times
分子等等，但你明白了
the numerator blah blah but you get it
好吧，八条线中有六条线
okay that's six of the eight lines the
第七行是我有双号
seventh line is if I have a dual number
我想转换它，你知道如何
I wanted to to convert it you know how
就像轮子嵌入了
like the wheels are embedded in the
复杂是你知道你只是我们必须
complex is you know you just we have to
告诉朱莉娅拿一个双号和
tell Julia to to take a dual number and
在坚持一个零，然后再双
stick a zero in in and then then dual
数字和常规数字可以完成
numbers and regular numbers can complete
很好地在一起，这实际上
nicely together and this this actually
如果我是真的说的话
is the thing that actually says if I
在一个数字中有一个双号
have a dual number in a number in
操作推动他们这样的工作为
operation promote them so the work as
双号码所以八行的代码，以便
dual numbers so eight lines of code so
我要告诉你的第一件事就是
the first thing I'm gonna tell you is
我要提醒你，你永远不会知道我
I'm going to remind you you never know I
从来没有输入一半X到负1/2
never typed one-half X to the minus 1/2
你不同意我没有进口的人吗？
do you agree no one I'm not importing
任何包装都不会像它来的那样
any packages it's not like it's coming
从我不是偷偷摸摸的
in from the I'm not sneaking it in from
旁边
the side
减去一个房子没有1/2X.
there's no 1/2 X to the minus a house
当然没有任何数字
and there's certainly not any numerical
衍生品或者恰到好处
derivatives either right just the just
可以说是几乎感觉到的规则
just arguably a rule that almost feels
符号中的商数规则
symbolic the quotient rule in the
添加规则，但没有数字
addition rule but but no numerical
这里的有限差异还可以
finite differences at all here okay so
所以首先让我告诉你
so first of all let me show you here
我正在接受我的申请
that I'm taking the I'm applying the
没有重写的巴比伦算法
Babylonian algorithm without rewriting
在我们之前的代码到双号
code to a dual number now before we
将它应用于数字，但现在我要去了
applied it to numbers but now I'm gonna
将它应用于这个双重数字
apply it to this dual number they're
刚发明我将在49岁时申请
just invented I'm gonna apply it at 49
一个因为我知道答案，然后我就是
one cuz I know the answer and then I'm
要把它与我拿一个进行比较
gonna compare it with I'm taking one
x的平方根的一半只是为了
half of a square root of x just for
比较目的是正确而非不是
comparison purposes right and not not in
我自己的算法，当然你看到了
my own algorithm and of course you see
我正在神奇地做对了
that I'm getting magically the right
没有任何答案你应该好奇
answer without ever so you should wonder
我怎么做的我是怎么得到的
how did I do that how did I get the
衍生品，我们可以采取任何数字你
derivative we could take any number you
如果您愿意的话，就像这里的一百个
like here's a hundred if you prefer to
看到一个像pi这样的数字我们可以做到这一点
see a number like pi we can do that I
意思是你知道我们可以做到这一切
mean you know we can do it every like
它会起作用所以你看到了
it's going to work so there you see that
这是pi和此的平方根
this is the square root of pi and this
将是一个一半以上的平方根
would be one half over the square root
pi数字，所以你看到它
of pi numerically so and you see it
将这些数字与这些数字相匹配
matches these these numbers to enough
实际上所有数字都是数字
digits in fact all the digits actually
是的，所以这件事神奇地工作好了
yeah so this thing magically worked okay
你应该都在想这是怎么回事
you should all be wondering how did that
发生
happen
对，我没有重写任何代码我
right I didn't rewrite any code I
实际上写了一个代码来计算一个
actually wrote a code to just compute a
平方根我从来没有写过
square root I never could never wrote a
用于计算平方导数的代码
code to compute the derivative of square
根源和顺便说一下这是一个
roots and and by the way this is a
那一点点朱莉娅的魔力
little bit of the Julia magic that that
我们正在推动数字是非常
we're pushing numerically that very
经常在这个世界上人们会
often and in this world people will
写一个代码来做某事然后如果
write a code to do something and then if
你想做更像get的事情
you wanted to do something more like get
有人写另一个的衍生物
a derivative somebody writes another
与朱莉娅的代码经常可以
code with Julia very often you can
实际上保持原始代码如果
actually keep to the original code if
你只需要使用它和正常
you just use it properly and
聪明地你可以做神奇的事情
intelligently you can do magic things
没有编写新代码，你会看到
without writing new codes and you'll see
这又是一点点但是这里
this again in a little bit but here's
你的衍生物知道这是
the derivative of you know this this is
的x的平方根的1/2的情节
the plot of 1/2 of the square root of x
在黑色，你可以看到
in black and again you could see the
在这里好好收敛我好
convergence over here all right well I'm
仍然不会告诉你为什么它的工作原理
still not going to show you why it works
只是还没有我保证我会和它的
just yet I promise I will and it's
可能还要多几分钟但是
probably a few more minutes more but
我首先要做的是我想
what I will do first is is I'd like to
向你展示大多数人的东西
show you something that most people
不要看我从不看它我
don't ever look at I never look at it I
想展示你在这里是相同的
want to show you here's the same
巴比伦代码我想告诉你
Babylonian code I want to show you the
用于计算的汇编程序
assembler for the computation of the
派生所以我要经营巴比伦人
derivative so I'm gonna run Babylonian
在双重数字上，我们会
on a dual dual number and we're gonna
看这里，我不知道是否有人
look here and I don't know if anybody
这里读取汇编程序我打赌有
here reads assembler I'm betting there's
实际上是零或一个人
zero or one of you actually
读了这些东西你们有多少人读过
reads this stuff how many of you read
汇编程序好吧我们得到它不是0-1
assembler okay we have got it wasn't 0-1
我们有一半是他的一半
we had a half right there's a half he's
有点像这样的箭头
kind of going like this here's the arrow
这是他喜欢的一个好吗
here's one he's like this okay
所以我认为零的是正确的
so so I think zero ones like the right
有点但我敢打赌，如果我，你会相信我
bit but I'll bet you'll believe me if I
告诉你，当你有短
tell you that when you have short
这样的汇编程序并不是很好
assembler like this and it's not very
很久以后你就拥有了高效的代码
long then you have efficient code but
它非常紧，它运行速度非常快
it's very tight it'll run very fast
所以不管这件事是做什么的
so whatever this thing is doing it's
简而言之，你不会得到任何
short and this you won't get from any
其他语言如果你确实尝试过
other language if you did try to do the
Python中我也向你保证
same thing in Python I promise you
他们将成为屏幕和屏幕
they'll be screens and screens and
即使你，屏幕也很丰富
screens full of stuff if even if you
能得到它所以这就是巴比伦人
could get it so so here's the Babylonian
双数的算法就在这里
algorithm on the dual number and here it
是一个汇编程序，它很短，所以
is an assembler and it's short so so the
我说的另一件事不仅仅是
other thing I'm saying is not only does
它有效，但朱莉也成功了
it work but Julie also makes it
在我终于告诉你之前，这样有效率
efficient so before I finally tell you
真正发生了什么以及它为何起作用
what's really going on and why it works
我要抓一个Python符号包
I'm gonna grab a Python symbolic package
这将与朱莉娅和
which will work nicely with Julia and
我将通过运行相同的代码
I'm going to run the same code through
Python象征性，并告诉你什么
the Python symbolic and show you what
这些是你的迭代
the these are the iterations that you
得到这是一个Khaleesi的
get so this is a Khaleesi the the
迭代朝向平方根和
iterations towards the square root and
这是迭代的
here are the iterations of the
实际存在的衍生物
derivative that's actually being
计算得到的，这里的关键点是
calculated um and the key point here is
当然，我们不是这个象征性的
of course we're not this is a symbolic
计算我们没有做一个象征性的
computation we're not doing a symbolic
计算这是数学上的
computation this is mathematically
相当于我们得到的功能
equivalent to the function we would get
如果我们喜欢绘制它或什么的
if we were to like plot it or something
但当然我们不是象征性的
but of course we're not symbolic
我的意思是计算效率非常低
computation is very inefficient I mean
你得到这些大系数我的意思
you get these big coefficients I mean
看看这个号码是什么这五
look at this number what is this five
无论如何，你得到的是万元
million or something anyway you get
这些人甚至是这些大数字
these big numbers these people even
这里更大的数字看这些巨大的
bigger numbers here look at these huge
数字正确，它需要很多
numbers right the it takes a lot of
存储我正在拖动这些X.
storage I'm dragging these X's along
记忆力有很大的拖累我的意思是这个
there's a big drag on memory I mean this
不是办法，这就是为什么我们做的
is not the way that this is why we do
数值计算但是什么
numerical computation but what the
巴比伦算法在没有
Babylonian algorithm in the absence of
任何舍入都等同于计算
any roundoff is equivalent to computing
你知道它正在计算的线上面
you know above the line it's computing
平方根在这里，然后在这里
the square root here and then below here
这是这些都是对迭代
this is these are the iterates towards
导数所以它实际上并非如此
the derivative so it's not actually
将X1/2X计算为负1/2
calculating X 1/2 X to the minus 1/2
它实际上在做一些迭代的事情
it's actually doing something iterative
差不多是1/2
that is approximating 1/2
-好吧，让我现在告诉你
- all right well let me tell you now let
我有点揭示正在发生的事情
me sort of reveal what's going on just
所以我可以告诉你它是怎么回事
so that I can kind of show you how it's
得到答案，就像我说的那样
getting the answer and like I said it
是SVD那种说服我的
was the SVD that sort of convinced me
这是怎么发生的，因为SVD是
how this was happening cuz the SVD is
也像这样的迭代算法
also an iterative algorithm like this
巴比伦方根，但它是
Babylonian square root but but it's
更容易向您展示与之相关的观点
easier to show you the point with the
胡扯和平方根所以我要做
baloney and square root so I'm gonna do
我永远不想做的事情
something that I would never want to do
这是明确写出衍生物
which is explicitly write a derivative
巴比伦算法和我正在做的事情
Babylonian algorithm and what I'm doing
我要采用2x的衍生规格
is I'm gonna take the derivative spec 2x
我的代码的每一行，所以你知道如果
of every line of my code so you know if
每条偶数或奇数线我都不知道
every even or odd line I never know
什么是偶数或奇数，但是
what's even or odd anymore but the
原始代码行有一个flex
original line of code had one flex over
两个现在我要采取衍生物
two now I'm going to take the derivative
或者在这里获得1/2
or get 1/2 here
如果我拿这个代码我就有这行代码
I had this line of code if I take the
衍生物我会使用的
derivative I'll use the the the the
商数规则，这将是
quotient rule and this would be the
如果我运行这个代码我会是衍生的
derivative if I run this code what I'm
有效的做法是我只是善用
effectively doing is I'm just using good
旧的加时间和分裂没有
old plus and times and divide nothing
看上去没有平方根
fancy there's not a square root to be
看到但我正在做的是当我跑我的
seen but what I'm doing is as I run my
算法我也在运行我其实
algorithm I'm also running I'm actually
如果我这样计算衍生物的话
computing the derivative as I go so if I
有这种无限的算法
have this infinite algorithm it's going
收敛到平方根此
to converge to the square root this the
衍生算法将收敛于
derivative algorithm will converge to
平方根的衍生物，但
the derivative of the square roots but
我不是我没有使用其他任何东西
I'm not I'm not using anything other
比加减次数除以得分
than plus minus times and divide to make
如果你重写任何代码就会发生这种情况
that happen so if you rewrite any code
在任何情况下你都可以迭代任何代码
at all you could have any code iterative
有限的，如果你只是无所谓
finite it doesn't matter if you just
把衍生品带回你的
take the derivatives back to your
你的代码的每一行的变量，然后
variable of every line of your code then
你可以得到一个衍生品，就像我一样
you can get a derivative out and as I
说这不是象征性的衍生品
said it's not a symbolic derivative like
你知道所有的1801或其他什么
you know all of 1801 or whatever
无论我们在哪里教微积分这些天
wherever we teach calculus these days
它不是像数字导数那样的
and it's not a numerical derivative like
在你知道的数字课程中
in a numerical courses that you know the
18.3XYZ是不同的
18.3 a X Y Z's whatever it's a different
野兽它是它的使用
beast it's the it's it's using the the
在加法法则商法则
quotient rule in the addition rule at
的每一步得到的答案
every step of the way to get the answer
所以，你知道这是这个d-bob
so and you know here's this d-bob
学习算法，你可以看到它
learning algorithm you could see it
跑步，我会得到它给予权利
running and I'll get it gives the right
回答我必须先执行代码
answer I have to execute the code first
得到正确答案，但你看到了
to get the right answer but you see it
给它给出正确的答案好吧哦
gives it gives the right answer okay oh
我只是在伊斯坦布尔，我可以
I was just in Istanbul and I they could
挑战我做招牌我忘了
challenge me to do sign I forgot about
它仍然在苏玛我的笔记本
that it's still in the Summa notebook I
它在我工作的每个人面前
it in front of everybody it worked I got
一个cosign好，但让我通过所有
a cosign okay but let me pass all of
那么那么让我回去告诉你
that so so so so let me go back and tell
那么这一切如何运作良好
you then how is this all working well
发生了什么让我们回到原点
what's happening let's go back to the
八行代码，现在也许你
eight lines of code and now maybe you
可以看到发生了什么事情
could see what's happening the where's
我的八行代码来自于
my eight lines of code from the very
一开始，我本可以看到
beginning and I could have watched the
时间我想告诉你这个
time I want to show you this one other
太有希望我会有足够的东西
thing too so hopefully I'll have enough
是时候这样做但是在这里让我们看看
time to do that but here let's see we
强大的大西洋代码在哪里
were mighty Atlantic code where are they
在这里，我们去你这里的事件
here we go you're here the events of
代码所以我正在做的不是
code so what I'm doing is instead of
通过获取所有代码来重写
rewriting all your code by taking the
以人的方式衍生出每一条线
derivative of every line the human way
我是说为什么不能用这个软件
I'm saying that why can't the software
只是以某种自动方式做到这一点
just do this in some automatic way and
这是自动的地方
this is where the automatic
分化进入旧的
differentiation comes in and in the old
所有的人在过去的日子
old days when people in all the
数字代码在Fortran那里
numerical code was in Fortran there
将是这些源到源
would be these source-to-source
实际输入的翻译
translators that would actually input
代码和代码的输出衍生物
code and output derivatives of code the
giulia方式更现代的方式是让
giulia way the more modern way is to let
JIT编译器就是这样做的
the JIT compiler kind of do that for you
所以在这里我需要它加分和
so here I need it plus and divide of
当然我想添加减号和
course I would want to add minus and
次，但你只需要添加一对夫妇
times but you just add a couple of
事情，然后撞你知道你
things and then bump the you know you
不必改写D巴比伦人
don't have to rewrite the D Babylonian
因为这种类型的巴比伦人
because the Babylonian with this type
我会为你做的工作好吗
will just will do the work for you okay
这就是善的魔力所在
and that's where the magic of a good
的软件都会有，所以你
piece of software will have it so you
不必写翻译你
don't have to write a translator you
没有手写的，你只要给
don't have to handwrite it you just give
一些规则，你让
sort of the rules and you let the
电脑做对了我的意思就是这样
computer do it right I mean that's what
计算机应该擅长和
computers are supposed to be good at and
这就是所有发生的事情
so that's that's what's happening all
对，这就是前进模式
right so that's that's forward mode
自动分化我有10个
automatic differentiation I've got 10
分钟往回走左右，但让我
minutes to go backwards so but let me
看看有没有人有
see if there's any anybody have any
关于这一点的问题，这是真的
questions about this this it's really
神奇的权利，但它非常棒
magic right but it's pretty wonderful
魔术和你知道我不知道
magic and and and you know I don't know
你听说过机器学习的内容
what you've heard about machine learning
但说实话
but to be honest
机器学习这些天就是它
machine learning these days it's it's
这是你知道忘记了
it's it's you know forgetting about
你是否知道人类将毫无用处
whether you know humans will be useless
我不相信，但是
which I don't believe by the way but but
关于机器的重要事情
the the the the big thing about machine
学习是真的只是一个大的
learning is that it's really just a big
一切都是正确的优化
optimization that's all it is right
你遇到的最小/最大问题
big minimum/maximum problem where you've
所有从微积分中知道你是什么
all known from calculus that what you
需要做的就是拿你知道的衍生物
need to do is take derivatives you know
将它们设置为零，你就知道了
set them to zero right you know in the
多元的情况下，这是一个梯度你
case of multivariate it's a gradient you
把它设置为零，所以真的这一切
set it to zero and so really all of this
机器学习所有的大故事和
machine learning all the big stories and
最终的一切都归结为一个
everything in the end comes down to a
自动微分是排序的
automatic differentiation is sort of
喜欢整体的主力
like the the workhorse of the whole
事情，所以如果我们可以有一个
thing and so if we could have a a
给你那个主力的语言
language that gives you that workhorse
以一种好的方式然后机器学习
in a good way then machine learning
这样做真的有点好处
really sort of benefits from that so so
我希望你们都能看到全局
I hope you all see the the big picture
机器学习真的来了
of machine learning it really does come
向下走衍生工具这
down to taking derivatives that that's
这就是你的结局
that's the end of that's how you
否则，优化任何快速问题
optimize any quick questions otherwise
我要转换主题，我要去
I'm gonna switch topics and I'm going to
移动到黑板是啊有一个
move to the blackboard yeah there's a
基本上让你去的技巧
trick that basically lets you go to
更高的订单是的，你基本上可以
higher orders yeah you can basically
使它成为两个第一顺序的组合
make it a combo of two first order
衍生物，所以是的，它可以做到
derivatives so yeah it can be done did
你有一个我们正在使用的问题
you have a question oh we're using for
使用类型所以这是最大的伎俩
using types so so it's the biggest trick
在世界上，这不是一件小事
in the world it's not this little thing
做一个类型来做你的想法
the idea of making a type to do what you
你有没有看到这个chroniker产品
did you see chroniker products in this
类没有什么好嗯，让我看看
class what no okay um let me see what
你会在这看到什么耶
what would you have seen in this yeah
你看到了三角形矩阵吗？
did you see tridiagonal matrices your
最喜欢的好，所以这里是一个
favorite okay so here so here's a
内置类型让我们说n是不是
built-in type let's say n is it doesn't
必须是四个我要创造一个
have to be four I'm gonna create a
Strang矩阵如果我拼写正确的话
Strang matrix if I could spell it right
它将是一个sim三角形
and it's going to be a sim tri diagonal
这是一种朱莉娅型，我们将创造
which is a julia type and we will create
N的两个x和n的n
two x ones of N and minus ones of n
减一，现在这里的类型我的意思是这个
minus one now here's a type I mean this
是内置的，但你可以创建
is built-in but you could have created
它本身也很容易，我不这样做
it yourself just as easily and I don't
喜欢打电话
like calling
这当然不是一个密集的矩阵
this it's certainly not a dense matrix
而且我不喜欢称之为稀疏
and I don't like calling it a sparse
矩阵我更喜欢称之为结构化
matrix I prefer to call it a structured
矩阵虽然稀疏这个词是一个
matrix though the word sparse it's a
这里有点棘手，但我之所以如此
little tricky here but the reason why I
不喜欢称之为稀疏矩阵
don't like to call this a sparse matrix
是因为我们没有存储索引
is because we're not storing indices in
任何我的意思是有很多想象力
any I mean there's a lot of fancy
存储指数的方案
schemes for storing indices for for
分数稀疏的矩阵很好
sparse matrices well the score store is
一个对角线矢量，这两个是
a diagonal vector there's the two's on
对角线有一个四向量
the diagonal there's a four vector with
四个二，这里是三个向量
four twos and here's a three vector for
对角线，你知道你没有
the off diagonal and you know you don't
以最稀疏的方式拥有它两次
have it twice by the way most sparse
矩阵结构会
matrix structures would would would
你会知道减去的吗？
would have you know the the minus ones
矢量两次超级和次级但
vector twice the super and the sub but
真的只有季度信息
really only the quarter information
这需要的是存储并在某种程度上一个
that's needed is stored and in a way one
在julia中使用的类型基本上就是你
uses types in julia to basically you
只存储你所需要的不是更多
only store what you need not more and
然后你定义你的运作
then you define your operations to work
所以，例如，如果我要带你
so for example if i were to take you
知道斯特朗逆时间如此
know Strang inverse time so anything
在这里是你知道的随机条款
with here's you know terms of random for
我会做一个线性的解决方案
I'm gonna do a linear solve you would
要使用特殊的回斯拉夫说
want to use a special back Slav that
知道矩阵是对称的
knew that the matrix was a symmetric
这是一个很重要的故事
tri-diagonal so it's a big story of
能够创建类型并使用它们
being able to create types and use them
为了你自己的目的，你不知道
for your own purposes without you know
任何浪费，这是一种事情
any wastage and this is a sort of thing
虽然你可以用语言来做
that while you can do it in languages
如果你是桌子，就像MATLAB中的Python一样
like Python in MATLAB if you were table
看看汇编程序和那个级别
look at the assembler and that level
永远不会让你呀
never let you Python you just would
后悔但是你会看到
regret it but you would you would see
这是多少开销
just how much overhead there is in doing
这样就没有性能提升
this so there'd be no performance gain
但在某种程度上，这就是你想要的
but in a way what this is what you want
做你想用这些东西来
to do you want to use these things to
匹配数学和所以那样
match the mathematics and and so that's
真的是能够做到的好事
really the nice thing to be able to do
没事我只有五分钟我
all right I only have five minutes I
不知道我是不是要把它拉下来
don't know if I'm gonna pull this off
但我会告诉我能不能给你
but I'll let me see if I could give you
在她的五分钟内的主要想法
the main idea in five minutes of her
沉浸式模式差异，但在这里
immersed mode differentiations but here
只要你熟悉神经
as long as you are familiar with neural
网络让我看看我是否能做到这一点
networks let me see if I can do this
我很快就会开始
very quickly I'm going to start with
scalars好吧我会做一个神经
scalars okay I'm gonna do a neural
所有标量的网络，但仅限于
network of all scalars but only for
简单的初学者，但我认为
simplicity for starters but I think
你会发现这可能是一般性的
you're gonna see that this can general
两个真实的向量和矩阵
two vectors and matrices which are real
神经网络，所以我要做的
neural networks so what I'm going to do
我想要想象我们有我们的
is I want to imagine that we have our
输入将有一堆标量
inputs will have a bunch of scalar
权重和偏见所以这里是w1和我
weights and biases so here's w1 and I'll
上升到W和B所以我们有一个
go up to W and B all right so we have a
一堆重量和偏见在这里没关系
bunch of weights and biases here okay
我们也将有一个x1
and we'll also have an x1 which will
排序开始我们的神经网络
sort of start off our neural network and
我们要计算我会写的
we're going to compute I'll write in
有点朱莉娅喜欢或MATLAB黑色
sort of Julia like or MATLAB black
I的符号等于1到n我会
notation for I equals 1 through n I will
通过我的一些功能来更新X.
update X by taking some function of my
当前输入可能是这样的
current input maybe something like this
什么功能H使用我不
and what function H to use I don't
在过去真的太在意了
really care too much in the old days
人们常常谈论乙状结肠
people used to talk about the sigmoid
现在的功能是最大值为0
function nowadays it's the maximum of 0
和T一直在使用它
and T that gets used all the time it's
得到了这个荒谬的名字
got this ridiculous name rel U which I I
无论如何他们真的受不了
really can't stand but anyway they
纠正线性单位但无论如何我
rectified linear unit but in any event I
意思是它只是一个功能
mean it it it's just a function that's
你知道的TT大于等于更大
you know T of T is greater than equal to
00，如果不是这样，但无论什么功能
0 0 if not so so but whatever function
你喜欢在这里我只是要
and you like and here I'm just gonna
最终你也可以更新Taemin
update Taemin ultimately you might also
有一些数据Y，你想
have some data Y and you would like to
如果一切都像我说的那样的标量
if everything is a scalar like I said
这可以很快推广
this could be generalized pretty quickly
但我们能做的就是尽量减少
but what we can do is we we can minimize
比如你知道的1/2Y减去XM平方
say 1/2 Y minus X M squared you know in
你想要找到的
the you're going to want to find the
数据可以最大限度地减少这一切
data that would minimize that ok all
这推广到矩阵和向量
this generalizes to matrices and vectors
这是大多数神经网络做得好的
which is what most neural nets do ok and
自从我不会有
since since since I'm not going to have
很多时候也许我可以只是有点
a lot of time maybe I can just sort of
如果我去的话，切入追逐
cut to the chase if I were to
区分我在这里的关键线
differentiate the key line here I've got
这里有一点朱莉娅，但如果我是
a little bit of Julia here but if I were
区分重点线会是什么
to differentiate the key line what would
我写道，我会在这里写得很好
I write I would write well here actually
让我用
let me use the
通常的记谱法让我有DeltaIB了
usual notation let me have Delta IB the
WXh的黄金我加双好了，这就是
H prime of WX i plus bi okay so that's
这是DeltaI然后你可以看到
that's Delta I and then you can see that
DXI加上一个是DeltaI，我会拥有
DX I plus one is Delta I and I'll have
DWIXI加DXIWI加dbi将是
DWI X I plus D X I WI plus d bi would be
差异这将是如何
the differential this would be how how
我几乎做到了这就是这样的善良
I'm almost done that's the goodness so
如果我做一点改变我喜欢
if I make a little change I like to
想到这就像点0:01的变化
think of this as like point 0:01 changes
我不喜欢我不喜欢无穷小
I don't like I don't like infinitesimal
一旦说到我的想法就像点O一样说
said like point O once it's how I think
他们但你做了一点改变
of them but you make a little change
这里有点变化
here a little change here a little
在这里改变你在这里得到改变
change here you get a change here you
你明白了，你知道你会得到这个
you'll get this you know you'll get this
线性的这个线性函数
linear this linear function of the
扰动在这里给你扰动
perturbations here gives you perturb
这里很好，我只有一个
ations here ok well I've only got one
分钟，所以我要写出这一切
minute so I'm gonna write all this out
用线性代数因为一切
with linear algebra because everything
用线性写出来更好
is better when written out with linear
代数所以我要写下我的意思
algebra so I'm gonna write down that I'm
要写下我实际上
gonna write down that I'm actually
对最后一个元素感兴趣但是dxdn
interested in the last element but dxd n
加1将是平等的，我会
plus 1 is going to equal and I'm gonna
这里有几个矩阵让我
have a couple of matrices here let me
只是让结构正确
just sort of get the structure right
这将是TX2DXn再加1
this will be T X 2 DX n plus 1 again
对不起压扁好吧但是
sorry for the squishing okay but and
这里其实我想用块
here in fact I'd like to use block
矩阵稍微如此，我会在这里
matrices a little bit so here I'm gonna
有DW1DB1我会放弃偏见
have DW 1 DB 1 I'm gonna put the bias
一起抱歉这个烂摊子和DW
together sorry for the mess but and DW
和DBn朱莉娅让你做块
and DB n Julia lets you make block
矩阵，你可以实际使用它们
matrices and you can actually use them
直接有一种特殊的类型权利
directly there'd be a special type right
没关系，然后你在这里发生了什么
there okay and then what goes here you
实际上可以看到它会是什么
could actually see what it would be
我希望我做得对，但是
would be I hope I'm doing it right but
有一个delta1X1和Delta和X.
there'd be a delta 1 X 1 and Delta and X
N和这将是对角矩阵
N and this would be a diagonal matrix
好的，然后我在这里有什么
okay and then what do I have over here
在这里，我有DeltaWS，如果你
here I'd have the Delta WS and if you
检查你会发现这将是我
check you'll see that this will be I'm
拿不到指数权和我
not gonna get the indices right and I
没时间，所以我要写
don't have time so I'm just gonna write
就像这样，现在我要去
it like this and now I'm just going to
告诉你故事的结局
give you the end of the story
你可以把所有这些写成DX
at a time you could write all this as DX
等于对角线矩阵乘以
is equal to a diagonal matrix times the
参数的导数加上a
derivative of the parameters plus a
再次下三角矩阵乘以DX
lower triangular matrix times D X again
所以如果你想解决这个问题
and so if you want to solve this linear
代数只做后向传播
algebra just does the back propagation
你有我减去LDX是DP或DX会
you have I minus L DX is d DP or DX will
如果我只是我减去L反DDP
be I minus L inverse D DP and if I only
想要最后一个元素让我们说E和as
want the last element let's say E and as
拉出最后一个的向量
the vector that pulls out the last
元素那么这就是我要去的
element then this is all I'm going to
需要得到我所有的衍生品和
need to get all my derivatives and
这个故事的寓意我是什么？
what's the moral of the story I
为一分钟而道歉但是
apologize for going one minute over but
道德的故事，而不是返回
the moral the story is instead of back
通过自己的辛勤劳动传播
propagating through your own hard work
你可能知道，当你解决一个
you probably know that when you solve a
下三角矩阵的人
lower triangular matrix people over a
编写代码，回传下层
written code that backhauls the lower
三角矩阵背面大背
triangular matrix the back the big back
这件作品已经实施了
piece has already been implemented for
你为什么要重新发明轮子呢？
you why do it why reinvent the wheel in
线性背面的反向传播
back propagation at the back of linear
代数已经有你看到我的后背
algebra already has the back you see I
意思是如果你只是这样做而你做到了
mean so if you just do this and you do
它用一种语言让你充实
it in a language to let you get full
你不需要做的全面表现
full performance you don't need to do
你自己的反传，因为a
your own back propagation because a
简单的反斜杠会为你做到这一点，所以我
simple backslash will do it for you so I
为过去而道歉我知道是否
apologize for going over I know if
斯特朗教授得到了一些最后的话
professor Strang got some final words
但无论如何线性代数是一个
but but anyway the linear algebra is a
一切都是秘密的
secret to everything that's that's the
大信息
big message
[掌声]
[Applause]
因为这是我们的最后两分钟或者减去
since it's our last two minutes or minus
1806年的两分钟五让我只是我
two minutes of 1806 five let me just I
希望你们喜欢它我当然
hope you guys enjoyed it I certainly
尽管你可以告诉它教导这个
enjoyed as you could tell teaching this
上课看看它会如何发展和写作
class seeing how it would go and writing
关于它
about it
所以我会告诉你的是关于
so I'll let you know was about the
写作，同时我会得到你的
writing and meanwhile I'll get your
写我的项目
writing on the projects which I
非常感谢，当然
appreciate very much and of course
成绩将会很好，我
grades are going to come out well and I
希望您喜欢它，谢谢大家
hope you've enjoyed it so thank you all
right thanks
好的，谢谢
[掌声]
[Applause]